Cloud Code is now available on the web.
So instead of loading up your terminal
or having to open up your IDE
anytime you want to make a change,
you can now delegate coding tasks
directly from your browser or the Cloud Mobile app.
You simply connect your GitHub account
you select your repo describe what you need done and claude handles the rest all running on our
cloud infrastructure and the best part is you can now run multiple tasks in parallel across different
repositories so whether you have a bug backlog routine fixes or a brilliant new idea or feature
you want to add you can just spin up a session or multiple sessions and let claude handle them
simultaneously let me show you how this works so i'll open up
cloudcode on the web at claw.ai slash code. I'll select a repo. I have a repo already selected here
and then I'll give it a prompt. Let's say add input validation to the user registration endpoint
Also make sure we're using a strong password on both the front end and back end API.
We'll hit enter and we are off the races.
Claude is working in his own isolated sandbox with full git access and we can watch the
progress in real time.
But while this runs.
let me tell you about some of the other stuff that we've recently launched.
The big one is Claude Haiku 4.5.
And a few weeks ago, we launched Claude Sonnet 4.5,
which became the world's best coding model.
And just last week, we followed it up with Claude Haiku 4.5.
And here's the really remarkable thing:
5 months ago, Sonnet 4 was state of the art.
And now, Haiku 4.5 gives you a similar coding performance
at one-third the cost and more than twice the speed.
It even surpasses Sonnet 4 at certain tasks like computer use.
Now, the benchmarks are impressive: 73.3% on SweetBench Verified,
41% on TerminalBench,
and it achieves 90% of Sonnet 4.5's performance
in agentic coding evaluations.
But the big question you're probably having is
when should developers use Haiku 4.5?
And the big pattern that we're seeing from our community
is that Sonnet 4.5 does the high level
problem decomposition and planning and then Haiku
4.5 is used to actually implement and write the code. Now this multi-agent
approach is becoming really popular for things like large-scale refactors or
tackling technical death. Haiku 4.5 is available wherever you get your clod and
it's available at just $1 per million input tokens and $5 per million output
tokens. Alright let's check
back on our task and see how it's doing. So if we open it up here we can see that
Claude gave us a good summary of all of the changes that it made in the service.go file,
in the TypeScript on the front end and my absolute favorite feature of Claude code on the web is this
open in CLI button and the reason that I really like it is you simply click it, you open up your terminal
paste in the command that it gave you.
And now I am working in my local development environment with all of the
context and all of my progress from the web preserve.
So I can see the messages.
I can see all of the files that have been changed.
I can go into VS code and see all of the changes that were made to the
service sign up.
the signup.type script file and much more and i can continue right from where i left off on my
mobile phone or the browser now i want to show you one final feature that we recently added to clot
code i gave it this prompt earlier talking about adding caching to my application but i gave it a
very broad prompt saying hey i would like to add caching to my application and what clot code did is
it's going to ask me a number of follow-up questions to make sure that it implements it correctly.
So it's going to ask the caching level here, should it be database query caching, API response caching,
and I can choose any of these, go to the next section and figure out what my goals are.
Is it to improve performance, reduce database load, the target area, is it for the workout data, for the user data,
analytics choose the technology redis in memory postgres and then i can hit submit and have it
go and implement based on the follow-up information that i gave it
and there you have it cloud code on the web for parallel cloud-based development at home
and on the go haiku 4.5 for lightning fast coding at a fraction of the cost
and smarter local workflows with multi-question support.
Cloud Code on the Web is available now for pro and max users at cloud.ai slash code.
Give it a try and let us know what you think.
Happy building.
you